Jiasheng Gu

Homepage GitHub LinkedIn Email: gujiashe@usc.edu Phone: +1 (213) 204-0294

Research Interests

I am interested in natural language processing and generation, machine learning, deep learning, and the study of reliable interconversion between natural language and different forms of data. My long-term research goal is to use artificial intelligence to turn natural language into a bridge to various tasks.

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

M.S. in Machine Learning and Data Science

Aug. 2021 - May. 2023

GPA: 4.0

Xidian University

Xian, Shaanxi

B.E. in Telecommunications Engineering

Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

GPA: *Top 10%*

Publications

Few-shot Code Generation via Rule-AI Co-learning from Document

Jiasheng Gu, Zifan Nan, Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng shen

In prep, ACL

Robustness of learning from task instructions

Jiasheng Gu, Hanzi Xu, Liangyu Nie, Wenpeng Yin

Submitted, EACL

Artificial Intelligence Related Techniques Used in Recent Bio-medical Publications

Jiasheng Gu, Lili Wang, Soroush Vosoughi

Submitted, Journal of Medical Internet Research (JMIR)

Research Experience

North Carolina State University

• Mentors: Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng Shen

Aug. 2022 – Present

- Project: Zero-shot Code Generation via Rule-AI Co-learning from Document
- Contribution: Proposed a zero-shot code generation framework combining rule-based and AI-based methods to generate DSL code.
- Publication: ACL in prep

University of Southern California

• Mentors: Peter A. Beerel

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Project: Designing visual networks with very low FLOPs
- Contribution: Proposed a dilated depthwise convolution that captures global information and extensive experiments are done on it.

Pennsylvania State University

• Mentor: Wenpeng Yin

June. 2022 - Oct. 2022

- Project: Robustness of learning from task instructions
- Contribution: Experimented and analyzed the robustness of the instruction-tuned model on perturbed instructions.
- Publication: EACL submitted

Dartmouth College

• Mentor: Soroush Vosoughi

May. 2022 - Sep. 2022

- Project: Analysis of artificial intelligence techniques used in biomedical publications
- Contribution: Proposed a method to analyze artificial intelligence techniques used in biomedical publications.
- Publication: JMIR submitted

University of Southern California

Mentor: Pedro Szekely

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

- Project: Integrating factual information from language models into knowledge graph embeddings
- Contribution: Improved link prediction task by factual information mined from language models via prompts.

University of Southern California

• Mentor: Massoud Pedram

Aug. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Project: Reduced-Memory-Access Inference of Deep Neural Networks
- Contribution: Integrated PyTorch distributed data-parallel framework into the flow to support multi-GPU processing.

ETH Zürich

• Mentor: Yuyi Wang

June. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Project: Designing pre-training tasks for text summarization
- Contribution: Using trained metrics to find the highest importance sentences as summaries makes the pre-training task more effective.

Industry Experience

Lime

• SDE internship

May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Reengineered a system for extracting and computing features to make it easier to modify feature definitions and compute features more efficiently.

Umer Technology

• NLP internship

Apr. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Deployed a medical named entity identification system via BERT+CRF.

Transwarp

• NLP internship

Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

Established an NLP system to summarize the text through Tensorflow in the environment built by Nvidia Docker.

Professional service

Program Committee

- The European Chapter of the ACL (EACL) 2023
- ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining(WSDM) 2023

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant, University of Southern California

• EE 503: Probability for Electrical and Computer Engineers

Fall 2022

• Grading course work and answering questions for students.

Awards

Master of Science (M.S.)

• Masters Students Honors Program (USC)

2021

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)

- ZTE Algorithm Competition, Regional Winner Award
- Third Class Scholarship (Xidian University)

20202019

Skills

Programming

Python, C++, C, R, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, MATLAB

Framework

PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, SciPy

Professional Softwares

Git, LaTeX, SPSS, Mathematica, AWS, GCP, Docker, MongoDB

References

Filip Ilievski, Assistant Professor

Viterbi School of Engineering University of Southern California ilievski@isi.edu

Peter A. Beerel, Professor

Ming Hsieh Electrical and Computer Engineering Department University of Southern California pabeerel@usc.edu EEB 350, 3740 McClintock Ave., Los Angeles, CA 90089

Soroush Vosoughi, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science
Dartmouth College
soroush.vosoughi@dartmouth.edu

Wenpeng Yin, Assistant Professor

Computer Science and Engineering Department Pennsylvania State University wenpeng.yin@temple.edu SERC376 1925 N 12th St, Philadelphia, PA 19122

Dongkuan Xu, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University dxu27@ncsu.edu 3258 EB II, 890 Oval Dr, Raleigh, NC 27695

Xipeng Shen, Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University xshen5@ncsu.edu